A Finding Aid to the George Leslie Stout papers, 1855, 1897-1978, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section Files, 1918; 1942-1955; 1972-1975; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 5, 10
  - Photographs, circa 1945; 5.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Miscellaneous Group Photographs of George Stout and Other Soldiers, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
      This folder includes a photograph of George Stout in front of a truck; a group photograph of Stout, Lamont Moore, Walker Hancock and other Monuments Men; and a few photographs of groups of unidentifed soldiers on a ship.
  - Diaries, 1944-1946; 5.4; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 10
    There are four diaries dating from 1944-1946 which describe George Stout's activities as a member of the MFAA Section during and after WWII while he was stationed in Europe and then Japan. There is also a short glossary of terms and quotations regarding Japanese tea ceremonies that was included with the diaries.
    The diaries are arranged in chronological order.
    The bulk of the diaries have been digitized, except for blank pages.
    - Diary 1, 1944 June-October; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Diary 2, 1944 October-1945 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Diary 3, 1945 June-August; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Diary 4 (Japan), 1945 September-1946 August; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Tea Ceremony Glossary of Terms and Quotations, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Personal Business Records, 1938-1978; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Linear feet Box 5, 7 folders
  The records in this subseries are assorted legal and financial papers, such as Stout's will and estate documents, receipts, travel expenses, and donations.
  The materials in this series have been arranged in chronological order.
  - George Leslie Stout's Will, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Estate and Property Papers, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Power of Attorney Papers, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Copyright Claim, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Court Case Over Johnson Estate Exhibition Paintings, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Receipts and Travel Expenses, 1942-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Signed Deed of Gift Agreeing to Donation of Conservation Roundtable Tape Recordings to FAIC, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Printed Materials, 1926-1977; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 5-6, OV 9
  Printed materials include news clippings, bulletins, brochures, conference papers, press releases and magazines.
  News clippings and articles about George Stout are grouped together at the beginning of the series in chronological order. The rest of materials are grouped together by type, i.e., books, brochures, newsletters, press releases, etc.
  The bulk of the materials in this series have been digitized except for duplicates. In some cases, publications have only had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages digitized.
  - News Clippings, 1930, 1940-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - News Clippings - Oversized, circa 1947; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - News Clippings, 1962-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - News Clippings - Oversized, 1969-1972; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings, 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - News Clippings - Oversized, 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - News Clippings - Oversized, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - News Clippings - Oversized, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 9)
  - News Clippings, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - News Clippings - Undated, circa 1945-circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Magazine and Journal Articles, 1926-1948; 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Magazine and Journal Articles, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Magazine and Journal Articles, 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Magazine and Journal Articles - Undated, circa 1945-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Books and Other Publications - Grace Cathedral, San Francisco, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Books and Other Publications - Oriental Art Auction Catalog, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Books and Other Publications - Studies in the History of Art, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Inscribed to George Stout from Richard Buck.
  - Books and Other Publications - New York State Award 1974, Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Books and Other Publications - Bronze Disease and its Treatment, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Brochures, 1945-1951; 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Brochures - Undated, circa 1950-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Memorial Tributes for Friends and Colleagues, 1962-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Museum Bulletins, 1936-1947; 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Museum Reports, 1963-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Newsletters & Announcements, circa 1971-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1954; 1971-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Review of The Care of Pictures, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1959-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Artwork & Sketchbooks, circa 1924-circa 1938; 1970-1977; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Linear feet Box 6
  Artwork consists of numerous sketches and one sketchbook by George Leslie Stout. The sketchbook is filled with figure drawings. Sketches are in pencil and ink of landscapes, animals, people and scenes from travels. Stout loosely grouped the sketches together by topic with titles such as "Pool Doodles" of people lounging by a poolside and "Pencil Studies Zoo, Park Studies," which are sketches of animals and landscapes. Stout also made holiday greetings cards for which he drew illustrations and added text. Photocopies of several of the completed greeting cards are included. There is one caricature of Eric Brown, Director of the National Gallery of Canada, by Murray Pease, Stout's friend and colleague.
  The materials in this series have been arranged in loose chronological order. One drawing by Murray Pease is at the end of the series.
  The bulk of the materials in this series have been digitized except for blank pages of sketchbooks.
  - Figure Drawing Sketchbook, circa 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Sketchbook of figure drawings of models.
  - Sketches, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Sketches of men playing baseball and three drawings of landscapes, 2 of unidentified locations and one of Oliver's Island, Thames in England dated 1938.
  - Greeting Card Designs - Photocopies, circa 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Pool Doodles" Sketches, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Several sketches of people lounging by a pool, location not specified. Sketches were grouped together by Stout along with the label "Pool Doodles."
  - Desert Sketches, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Sketches grouped together in a folder with an insert labelled "desert." Drawings depict objects such animal skulls and pieces of driftwood. There are two landscapes of an unidentified location.
  - Hilandar Monastery on Mt. Athos, Greece Sketches, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Pencil drawings of Hilandar Monastery on Mount Athos in Greece dated August, 1971. Drawings are probably from a trip Stout took to the location. The images depict the interior and exterior of the monastery as well as the surrounding landscape. Many drawings have annotations such as "from the window of Room No. 3, Monastery of Hilandari. August 1971."
  - Park and Zoo Sketches, 1977; 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
    These drawings were grouped together by Stout along with the label "Pencil Studies Zoo, Park Studies." These include a few ink drawings of people, trees, and park scenes which Stout drew at Balboa Park in California. There are also some pencil sketches of Scandavian reindeer and Uganda Kob which he drew at the zoo.
  - Caricature of Eric Brown by Murray Pease, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Photographs and Negatives, 1897-1978; circa 1855; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 6-7
  This series includes photographs, negatives, contact prints, and a few slides of Stout, his friends and colleagues, travels, and events such as arts conservation conferences and receptions.
  Photographs of George Stout are at the beginning of the series, followed by photographs of other people (family, friends, and colleagues), gatherings and events, and travel photographs of various locations.
  The bulk of the materials in this series have been digitized, except for blank versos of photographs and duplicates.
  - George Stout Childhood Photos, circa 1897; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - George Leslie Stout Portraits, circa 1965-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - George Stout Snapshots, Mostly with Other People, circa 1945-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - George Stout's Self-Portraits (Photographs of Drawings), 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - A. R. Stout, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Micajah and Abraham Lincoln Stout, circa 1855; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Two of the photographs are cartes de visite.
  - Friends and Acquaintances, circa 1940; circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Individuals, 1930-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "Conservation Personnel" at Conferences and Meetings in Rome and Paris, 1930-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Conservation Projects for Paintings, circa 1955-circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fogg Art Museum Class, 1928-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - International Congress of the History of Art, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lisbon Reception, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Live Oaks, California, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mexico Trip, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Palo Alto, California, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reno, Nevada, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - San Simeon, California, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sharon Green, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Locations, circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)